<resources>
    <string name="app_name">My Guide</string>
    <string name="udaygiri">UDAYGIRI-KHANDAGIRI CAVES</string>
    <string name="udaygiri1">
        Timimg: 8:00 AM-5:00 PM |        Visit Duration:2 to 3 hours
    </string>
    <string name="udaygiri2">
        Entry Fee: ₹ 15 per person(if Indian)/ ₹ 200 per person(if foreign national)\n
    </string>
    <string name="udaygiri3">
        The multi-tiered rock-cut caves of Udayagiri (ancient Skandagiri) and Khandagiri symbolise Jainism’s cameo role in Orissa’s historical drama. Commissioned by the great Jain king Kharavela, they were meant as dwellings for Jain monks. Udayagiri means "Sunrise Hill" and has 18 caves while Khandagiri has 15 caves. Much of the art in the caves hasn’t survived. But whatever has remained suggests a fine degree of sophistication.\n It’s best to take a guide along, as there are no signposts. Cave 4 or Rani Gufa in Udayagiri is a two-storeyed structure with attractive, even if mutilated, sculptures. Cave 10, Ganesh Gufa, has a beautiful statue of Ganesha and two elephants standing guard outside.\n
        "Archaeological Survey of India has listed Udayagiri and Khandagiri Caves in the list of "Must See" Indian Heritage."The caves of Udayagiri and Khandagiri, called lena or leṇa in the inscriptions, were dug out mostly during the reign of Kharavela for the abode of Jaina ascetics. Other important caves include Hathi gumpha, Ananta gumpha,Jaya Vijaya gumpha, Mancapuri gumpha, Bagha/Byaghra/Vyaghra gumpha and Sarpa gumpha.
    </string>
    <string name="lingraj">LINGARAJ TEMPLE</string>
    <string name="lingaraj1">
        Timings : 5:00 AM-9:00 PM  |    Visit Duration:1-2 hours
    </string>
    <string name="lingraj2">
        Entry Fee : Free
    </string>
    <string name="lingraj3">
        The Lingaraj Temple is an ancient temple situated in the city of Bhubaneswar and is the largest one situated in the city. Dedicated to Lord Shiva as the name suggests, the temple was built in the 7th century by the King Jajati Keshari. It is highly revered because of the fact that the Linga here, which is the phallic form of Lord Shiva, is believed to have appeared naturally. It rises to a massive height of 8 inches above the floor level and is about 8 feet in diameter as well. Lingaraj Temple is located in the old part of Bhubaneswar Town and can be easily reached using local transport.\n
        The edifice of the temple is a great example of the Odissi style of architecture and has intricately designed stone vaults covering the main sanctum of the temple.  A small temple dedicated to Goddess Bhagawati is located in the northwest corner of the courtyard as well.\n However, entry is restricted to the followers of the Hindu faith only. The Lingaraj Temple is especially famous for its Mahashivratri celebrations when the whole sanctum is dressed up in flowers, lanterns, and lights. The temple has as many as 6,000 visitors on a daily basis with Shivratri being a major day of celebrations when this number surges to as many as 200,000 visitors.
    </string>
    <string name="Ram_Mandir">SRI RAM MANDIR</string>
    <string name="Ram_Mandir1">
        Timings: 6 AM-9.30 PM   |      Visit Duration:1-1.5 hours
    </string>
    <string name="Ram_Mandir2">
        Entry Fee: Free
    </string>
    <string name="Ram_Mandir3">
        At a distance of 1.5 km from Bhubaneswar Railway Station, Shri Ram Mandir is a beautiful temple situated near Kharavel Nagar in Bhubaneswar. Situated in the heart of city, it is one of the most famous temples for the devotees of Lord Rama and also one of the pilgrimage places to visit in Bhubaneswar City.\n
        The temple is dedicated to Lord Rama, an incarnation of Lord Vishnu. The temple is home to the beautiful images of Lord Rama, Lord Lakshmana and Goddess Sita. Built and managed by a private trust, the temple complex also comprises shrines devoted to Lord Hanuman, Lord Shiva and other gods. The idols are beautiful and garden in front of temple is well maintained. One can spend the whole evening with evening aarti with great peace of mind and spiritual feeling.\n
        This newly built temple is characterized by large spires which can be visible from many parts of the city. The major festivals celebrated are Ram Navami, Vivaha Panchami, Janmashtami, Dussehra, Shivaratri, and Pana Sankranti. Annual fair is also organized here on the occasion of Raksha Bandhan or Rakhi. The magnificent aarti during morning and evening draws a lot of devotees.
    </string>
    <string name="Mukteshwar_Temple">MUKTESHWAR TEMPLE</string>
    <string name="Mukteshwar_Temple1">
        Timings: 6:30 AM-7:30 PM   |     Visit Duration:1-1.5 hrs
    </string>
    <string name="Mukteshwar_Temple2">
        Entry Fee: Free
    </string>
    <string name="Mukteshwar_Temple3">
        Located in the capital city Bhubaneswar, the Mukteshwar temple is a brilliant structure, which is dedicated to Lord Shiva. Well-known as the \"Gem Of Odisha Architecture"\, the Mukteshwar Temple is a regal monument that dates back to the 10th century BC. It is a prime tourist attraction that comes under the Protected Monuments of India.\n
        The Mukteshwar Temple is the finest example of a perfect blend between sculpting and architecture. Several shrines or lingas of Lord Shiva can be found in the temple. Various sculptures of ascetics forming different meditating poses can be found all around the temple.\n
        It is speculated that the temple was built by Yayati I, the king of Somavamshi Dynasty. The west-facing structure of this temple reflects a change in the initial and later phase of Kalinga style of architecture, which was the main style used in many temples built in Odisha during the time.
        \nThe torana or the elaborately decorated arch is the main feature of this temple. It reflects heavy influences from Buddhist architecture. The archway or torana has exquisite carvings of ornaments, beautiful women and other such intricate designs.\n
        The pyramidal roof of the temple's Jagamohana or the assembly hall, is first of its kind. Everything about the temple, that is its sanctum, the temple plan, the porch, reflect top-class architectural brilliance.
    </string>
    <string name="museum">ODISHA STATE MUSEUM</string>
    <string name="museum1">
        Timings: 10:00 AM-5:00 PM   |     Visit Duration:2-3 hours
    </string>
    <string name="museum2">
        Entry Fee: ₹ 10 (Indians)/ ₹ 50(Foreigner)
    </string>
    <string name="museum3">
        In 1932, Prof. N.C. Banerjee and Prof. Ghanshyam Dash, two notable historians of Ravenshaw College in Cuttack, started this Odishan museum. They collected a great assortment of archaeological treasure from various places and kept them in a small museum which was then located in the college premises. Later in 1938, it was transformed into state’s primary museum by the government.\n
        However, in 1947-48, when the state capital of Odisha shifted from Cuttack to Bhubaneswar, the museum got shifted as well, and thus, the present structure of the museum is located in the capital city of Bhubaneshwar. With time, the museum flourished, and finally, on 29 December 1957, the foundation stone of the present structure of the museum was laid. In 1960, the construction work of the museum got completed and was also shifted to a new building. In the same year, the museum renamed as Odisha State Museum.\n
        On the display, the museum boasts an exquisite collection of sculptures, numismatics, antiquities, copper plates, and specimens. All the arts and artefacts here at the state museum offers an insight into rich India as well as Odisha heritage. Apart from this, the main highlight of this beautiful museum is the stone sculptures that are categorized into three groups defining their style. These styles include Gandhara Art, Odishan Art, and North Indian Art.
    </string>
    <string name="IIT">Indian Institute Of Technology, Bhubaneshwar</string>
    <string name="IIT1">Type: Public technical university</string>
    <string name="IIT2">Established: 2008; 12 years ago</string>
    <string name="IIT3">
        Indian Institute of Technology Bhubaneswar (IIT Bhubaneswar) is a public technical and research university established by the government of India in 2008, located at Bhubaneswar, Odisha, India. It is one of the eight new Indian Institutes of Technology (IITs) established by the Ministry of Human Resource Development, Government of India under The Institutes of Technology (Amendment) Act, 2011 which establishes the eight new IITs as well as declares IIT-BHU as Indian Institute of Technology.\n The Act was passed in the Lok Sabha on 24 March 2011 and by the Rajya Sabha on 30 April 2012. It started functioning from the campus of IIT Kharagpur on 23 July 2008 and shifted its operation to the city of Bhubaneswar on 22 July 2009.
        \nThe institute admits students into BTech, MTech and PhD programs. It started operating from current campus at Arugul from academic session 2015–16. The new and permanent campus was inaugurated by Narendra Modi on 24 December 2018.\n Admissions are done as per the All India Rank of JEE Advanced. The academic session begins in July each year. Currently, Prof. R.V. Rajakumar is the director of the institute.
        \nHistory:\n
        Establishing an IIT in Odisha was a long-standing demand for several decades. As the state ranked at the bottom in terms of centrally funded academic and research institutions, there were strong allegations of Congress led central government neglect. There were several incidents of protest, both locally in Odisha, the National Students Union of India (NSUI), and eminent nonresident Indian academics.
        \nIn May 2007, this became a major issue in the Indian parliament. The opposition NDA staged a walk-out in the Indian parliament, accusing the ruling UPA of neglecting the state\'s economic development. Sections of the media reported that the Congress party led UPA government had been embarrassed by this issue. Eventually, the HRD minister Mr. Arjun Singh relented, leading to the inception of IIT Bhubaneswar.\n
        Hostel / Housing: \n
        Hostel facilities to students have been provided through a 200 capacity Dr. A. N. Khosla Hall of Residence of IIT Kharagpur near its Extension Center. In addition, the Institute has two hostels (started in July 2015) at its permanent campus, Mahanadi Hall of residence(MHR) of 800 capacity for boys and Subarnarekha Hall of Residence(SHR) for girls of 200 capacity. The Institute has also provided housing facility for the Faculty members and the staff members at its campus, Faculty Quarter(FQ) and Staff Quarter(SQ).
    </string>
    <string name="KIIT">Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology</string>
    <string name="KIIT1">Type: Private</string>
    <string name="KIIT2">Established: 1992</string>
    <string name="KIIT3">Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology (KIIT), formerly KIIT University, is a private institute deemed to be university located in Bhubaneswar, Odisha, India. The institution offers undergraduate and post-graduate courses in engineering, bio-technology, medicine, management, law, computer application, rural management, fashion, film studies, journalism, architecture and sculpting. It was recognised as an Institute of Eminence in 2019.\n
            KIIT ranked 1st in India in the 2020 ARIIA Ranking published by the MHRD under the \'Private or Self-Financed Universities\' category. In the NIRF Rankings announced on 11 June 2020, KIIT\'s rank improved to 44th from 50th in the Overall category, while it was ranked 24th in the rank for University.\n Recently, KIIT has won \'The Awards Asia\' 2020 which was declared by the Times Higher Education (THE).\n
            History:\n KIIT was established in 1992 as an Industrial Training Institute with only twelve students and two faculty.[5] This institution was the brainchild of Achyuta Samanta, C R Mishra, P K Mishra who had envisioned a profound center of learning in India and so pursued to lay the foundation of KIIT. In 1997, the School of Technology and the School of Computer Application was established. In 2004 it was conferred the status of deemed university and renamed KIIT University.\n
            Rankings:\n The National Institutional Ranking Framework (NIRF) ranked Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences 32 overall in India in 2020 among medical rankings.\n
            Academics:\n
            Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences provides degree courses for MBBS, MD and MS. Its intake for MBBS courses is 150 and for postgraduate courses it is approximately 75 seats. It offers post graduation in more than 18 subject including medicine and general surgery. A dental wing in the college campus imparts B.D.S. and M.D.S. degrees under the KIIT University.
    </string>
    <string name="KIMS">Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences</string>
    <string name="KIMS1">Type: Private</string>
    <string name="KIMS2">Established:	2007</string>
    <string name="KIMS3">
        Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences (KIMS) is the medical school of the Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology situated in Bhubaneswar, Odisha, India. This institute began offering MBBS courses in medical stream courses in 2007.\n
        Its sister institute offering dental courses is the Kalinga Institute of Dental Sciences (KIDS).\n
        History:/n
        The idea of a medical college was conceived by Achyuta Samanta.[citation needed] Construction of the college building was completed in 2004, the faculties were appointed. Initially, the hospital was a makeshift facility in the Godown area of the former MAGNETIC company. This hospital was extended to take up more indoor patients and service was improved.
        In June 2005 the new hospital building was complete. The hospital acquired new equipment like a CT scan.\n
        2006 saw the beginning of the inspection processes by the MCI and in June 2007 KIMS was formally given permission to start MBBS course.\n
        The institute was earlier affiliated to Utkal University, however in 2009 in came under the ambit of KIIT University. In 2013, KIMS got permanent affiliation from Medical Council of India (MCI).\n
        Rankings:\n
        The National Institutional Ranking Framework (NIRF) ranked Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences 32 overall in India in 2020 among medical rankings.\n
        Academics:\n
        Kalinga Institute of Medical Sciences provides degree courses for MBBS, MD and MS. Its intake for MBBS courses is 150 and for postgraduate courses it is approximately 75 seats. It offers post graduation in more than 18 subject including medicine and general surgery. A dental wing in the college campus imparts B.D.S. and M.D.S. degrees under the KIIT University.
    </string>
    <string name="AIIMS">All India Institute of Medical Science</string>
    <string name="AIIMS1">Type: Public Medical College</string>
    <string name="AIIMS2">Established:   2012</string>
    <string name="AIIMS3">
        All India Institute of Medical Sciences Bhubaneswar (AIIMS Bhubaneswar), formerly Netaji Subhas Chandra Bose All India Institute of Medical Sciences, is a medical college and medical research public university located in Bhubaneswar, Odisha, India. The institute operates autonomously under the aegis of the Ministry of Health and Family Welfare. It was established in 2012 and the foundation stone was laid by late (Bharat Ratna)Shri. Atal Bihari Vajpayee on 15 July 2003.
        \n AIIMS Bhubaneswar is situated on the outskirts of Bhubaneswar. It was built on about 100 acres of land in the Sijua neighborhood of Bhubaneswar. Vipul Green Tower is present opposite to the Main Hospital Gate] AIIMS – Bhubaneswar is divided into three sections: a hospital, medical college, and residential complex.\n
        The AIIMS Campus extends over 100 acres, consisting of the hospital complex and residential area. The hospital complex consists of a 900-bed multi speciality hospital with 43 departments. The Academic Area present in the complex houses the Academic Block, College of Nursing and Central Library. The Academic Blocks consists of 4 Lecture Halls and Departmental Labs of Anatomy, Physiology, Biochemistry, Pathology, Microbiology, Pharmacology, Forensic Medicine, Community Medicine.\n
        \nThe hospital has a total of 43 Departments including the pre clinical, para clinical, speciality and super speciality departments. It houses about 920 beds including private beds with 40 additional disaster beds. A New Trauma Level 1 Centre and Burn Speciality Building is under construction. A 500 Bed Patient Relative Resting Shelter "Dharamsala" supported by NALCO is also completed and will soon be opened for public use.
    </string>
    <string name="NISER">National Institute of Science Education and Research </string>
    <string name="NISER1">Type: Public Autonomous Institute of Higher Studies</string>
    <string name="NISER2">Established:    2006</string>
    <string name="NISER3">
        The National Institute of Science Education and Research (NISER) is an autonomous premier public research institute in Jatani (Khordha), Odisha, India under the umbrella of Department of Atomic Energy, Govt. of India. The institute is a constituent institution of Homi Bhabha National Institute (HBNI) and one of the best in the country in the field of basic science and research mainly known for its quality education and infrastructure and is intended to be the leading institute in the country in the field of basic sciences and research.\n The prime minister, Manmohan Singh (2004–2014), laid the foundation stone on August 28, 2006, establishing the institute along the lines of the IISc in Bangalore, and its seven sister institutions, the IISERs, established at Pune, Mohali, Kolkata, Bhopal, Berhampur, Tirupati and Thiruvananthapuram in India.\n
        Unlike the IISERs, which will be governed by the Ministry of Human Resources Development, Government of India, NISER operates under the umbrella of the Department of Atomic Energy (DAE).\n
        \nNISER is dedicated to undergraduate and graduate education and research only. It offers a five-year integrated MSc as well as PhD degrees in pure and applied sciences. Degrees at NISER will be awarded by the Homi Bhabha National Institute (HBNI), a deemed-to-be University within the Department of Atomic Energy.\n
        \n Rankings:\n
        National Institute of Science Education and Research (NISER), Bhubaneswar was ranked 14 in the university category and 30 overall in India by National Institutional Ranking Framework (NIRF) in 2020. It is a Constituent Institution of Homi Bhabha National Institute so the ranking of Homi Bhabha National Institute is considered the ranking for all of its constituent institutions.\n
        The National Entrance Screening Test or NEST[19] is a compulsory test for admission to the 5-year Integrated MSc programme in basic sciences.\n
        The Odisha government had provided 300 acres (1.2 km2) for the permanent campus near Barunei Hills, between Bhubaneswar, the state capital and Khurda. This location is a few km southwest of Bhubaneswar. The institute is located at Jatani, about 20  km away from Biju Patnaik International Airport.
    </string>
    <string name="OUAT">Odisha University of Agriculture and Technology</string>
    <string name="OUAT1">Type: Public</string>
    <string name="OUAT2">Established:    1962</string>
    <string name="OUAT3">
        Odisha University of Agriculture and Technology (OUAT) was established in Bhubaneswar, Odisha, India in 1962. It is the second oldest agricultural university in the country. It is dedicated to agriculture related research, extension and education. The University has 11 constituent colleges. The University has separate wings for research, extension services and planning, monitoring and evaluation, etc.\n
        \n The university aims to provide quality education in agricultural science and technology. The university offers the following degrees: B.Sc. (agriculture), M.Sc. (agriculture), B.Sc. (forestry), B.V.Sc. and A.H., M.V.Sc., B.Tech., M.Tech., B.Sc. (Home.Sc.), B.F.Sc., M.F.Sc.,+2 Science, B.Sc. (Pass and Hons), MBA (Agribusiness Management), MCA., M.Sc. (Micro Biology), M.Sc. (Bioinformatics) M.Sc. (physics, chemistry, math, botany, and zoology) and Ph.D. in some of the selected branches such as Ph.D. in Zoology, Botany, Physics, Mathematics and Microbiology.\n
        \n The University has strengthened its research and extension base by establishing eight Zonal Research Stations, four Zonal Sub-stations, 7 Commodity Research Stations and 13 Adaptive Research Stations spread over the state/ along with 48 All India Coordinated Research Projects. Also, more than 41 National Agricultural Technology Projects are in operation. A number of ad-hoc projects funded by different external agencies are also implemented in the University.
    </string>
</resources>